Profile — Web developer

A Computer Engineer with more than 9 years of professional experience and strong skills in web development, frontend and User Experience design. I'm also a very enthusiastic and creative person, with extensive knowledge of graphic design, branding and identity, interaction patterns, usability and SEO.

Professional Experience

ThoughtWorks Inc. February 2012 — Current

Consultant involved in different projects and applying the following skills:

Developer: Test-Driven Development and Behaviour-driven development with Ruby and Sinatra framework, infrastructure as code (devops) using puppet and fabric, agile methodology, continuous delivery and one-click deployment using Go.

Experience Design: graphic design, user experience, user testing, guerrilla testing and research, production-ready frontend skills with CSS3 and HTML5 responsive websites. Managing Stakeholders, MVP design, inception facilitator and prototype development.

Alquimia Proyectos Digitales March 2007 — January 2012

Leader of frontend team, developing SEO optimized, W3C valid HTML and CSS top quality themes, including projects with short deadlines, usability-oriented, cross-browser and legacy browser compliant, modifying and improving external themes or working as a team with other leading companies.

UNICEF España — http://www.unicef.es and http://tienda.unicef.es

Theming and Information Architecture design for corporative site and ecommerce shop, collaborating with a partner software development company, managing complex theming development including some custom code.

United Nations (UN) — http://www.sinexcusas2015.org

Rapid theming and backend development dealing with legacy code from an external company, client communication and custom development.

Spanish Official Vaccine Advisory Committee — http://www.vacunasaep.org Spanish Association of Pediatrics — http://www.aeped.es/

Graphic design from scratch, cross-browser themes, client communication and user experience.

Webalquimia — http://al.quimia.net

Full multilanguage company website with mobile-first design, including visual graphicdesign from scratch, Information Architecture development, responsive HTML5 and CSS3 themes.

Andalusian Regional Government — Drupal course teacher for Instituto Andaluz de Administración Pública.

More than 30 different projects from Drupal 4.7 to Drupal 7 — Including frontend and backend development, content types definition and implementation, module development, ecommerce websites, customizing third-party themes an graphic design.

Freelance web developer, modifying and creating from scratch some handmade websites and working with different CMS — Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal — from 2005 to 2007

Humiservi Climatización y Control, S.A — Main role of User Interface designer in a C++ SCADA system for house and industry automation project, developing a fully programmable GUI.

Unión Grafijerez artes gráficas — Two-month internship in a printing house, working as graphic and layout designer.

Education

Computer Science BsC — Spanish pre-Bolognia equivalent, ITIG. University of Cadiz (Spain) — 2004/2011

Highest grade for **Final Year Thesis** — Multiplatform dominoes game developed with Python and using Expert Systems for its Artificial Intelligence, available at http://dominous.forja.rediris.es/

Technical Skills

Programming languages PHP, Python, C/C++, Ruby, JavaScript

Web Frontend HTML5/CSS3 semantic, accessible and maintainable markup code

Database management MySQL, Oracle

Graphic design Vector and bitmap software — Adobe and Corel suites

Control Version Systems SVN, GIT

Operating Systems GNU/Linux, Windows and Mac OSX

Courses, congress and seminars

Kevin Werbach **Gamification course** with 94.65% completion grade — University of Pennsylvania.

National an international congress and seminars attendance about Computing Science and web development

- **BBC Developer Conference** Big Data (SQL & NoSQL) 2012.
- Different **Drupal congress** Drupalcamp Barcelona 2007, Sevilla 2011, Manchester 2013.
- Social network and blogging congress **EBE** Sevilla 2009, 2011.
- I, II, III, IV Free Libre Software conference of University of Cadiz. 2004, 2005, 2006 and 2009 years.
- I and II Open Source World Conference, 2004 and 2006. Palacio de Ferias y Congresos de Málaga.
- II New technologies seminar. Cadiz Council Diputación de Cádiz and REI, 2004.
- Intellectual Property, Free Libre Software and University 2006, Libre Software and Open Knowledge
 Office, University of Cadiz.
- Secure software development seminar. E-Business, Social Science and Communication Technologies and Jerez Business School, 2006.

Additional information

- **First Prize** in atrÉBT! Entrepeneur University Contest.
- Paper author and workshop about "Editing digital audio with Audacity" in Free Libre Software conference of University of Cadiz. ISBN13: 978-84-9828-055-5
- Active collaboration in **Xinug Computer Association**, organizing activities, seminars and Lan Parties, working in:
 - Logistics and network deployment.
 - Visual branding design with posters, flyers, t-shirts and more.
 - Competition judge and graphic design contest organizer.
- Organizer and visual branding graphic designer for FLOSS Free/Libre/Open Source Systems
 International conference.
- Scientific paper translation for NovÁTIca (Spanish National Computer Science Journal)
- Cover and back design for "Eres Dulce" diabetes self-help book.